Ritesh Firodiya



firodiya.ritesh@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/riteshfirodiya



(+91) 9226737797



https://riteshf.deno.dev

Summary

I'm a full-stack developer with 5+ years of experience in software development and am a JavaScript enthusiast. with experience in domains like banking, finance, auditing, identity and access management, food and delivery, and ed-tech. I'm proficient in Javascript, Typescript, React, Node, Deno, and GraphQL, and I am open to learning anything required to build quality products. In my professional career, I've had the opportunity to work with a wide range of companies, from product-based to service-based, from a startup to a multinational corporation, with responsibilities ranging from teaching technology to team management to architecting projects from the ground up.

Experience

masai Senior Software Engineer

Masai

Oct 2021 - Present (1 year 2 months +)

Masai is in the edu-tech domain. Here, I teach MERN coding, while managing teams for internal development, and I do hiring and take interviews as well.



Senior Software Engineer

Swiggy

Nov 2020 - Sep 2021 (11 months)

Swiggy is the market leader in the food and delivery business. While I was a contract employee via Recro, here I worked on technologies like React and Node. Our responsibilities were to design and implement efficient solutions to make it easier for restaurants to manage their customers.

G>

Senior Software Engineer

Globant

Sep 2019 - Nov 2020 (1 year 3 months)

Globant is a service-oriented company with over 700 active projects. Here, we worked on technologies like React and Node in the domain of banking and finance. Our responsibilities were to design and implement efficient web components to be integrated with banking servers and guide the team in achieving pixel-perfect requirements.



Software Engineer

Confluxsys

Jun 2017 - Sep 2019 (2 years 4 months)

Confluxsys specialises in identity and access management as well as business analytics; I worked as a full stack engineer there. As a start-up, I used to wear various hats. while working on technologies ranging from Java in the back-end to React in the front-end and Postgresql and Oracle as databases while integrating with OIM and Sailpoint.

Education



Pune Vidyarthi Griha

Bachelor, Computer Engineering

Skills

React.js • TypeScript • JavaScript • Node.js • GraphQL • Express.js • WebSocket • MongoDB • PostgreSQL • Redis